RAO MUHAMMAD UMER













Research Statement

My research revolves around a broad spectrum of **image restoration** problems, particularly in image super-resolution, image deblurring, and image denoising.

Research Interests

Computational Imaging, Image Restoration, Camera pipeline, Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Medical Imaging.

Education

Nov 2018 - 2021 PhD in Industrial and Information Engineering, University of Udine, Udine, Italy.

Research Area: Computer Vision and Deep Learning

Nov 2014 - 2016 MS in Computer Science, Pakistan Institute of Engineering and Applied

Sciences, Nilore, Islamabad, Pakistan.

Area: Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning

CGPA: 3.45/4.0, ranked in top 5% of the class.

SEP 2010 - 2014 BSc. in Computer Systems Engineering, The Islamia University of

Bahawalpur, Bahawalpur, Pakistan.

Major Subjects: AI, Parallel and Distributed Computing, Image Processing

CGPA: 3.82/4.0, ranked in top 5% of the class.

SEP 2008 - 2010 FSc. in Pre-Engineering, Government Post Graduate College, Sahiwal,

Major Subjects: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

Percentage average: 86%, 943/1100 Marks.

Mar 2006 - 2008 Matriculation in Science, Lasani Public High School, Sahiwal, Pakistan.

Major Subjects: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology

Percentage average: 92%, 783/850 Marks.

Professional Experience

Dec 2017 - Sep **Research Fellow**, Computational Imaging Group (CIG) at the Skolkovo Institute 2018 of Science and Technology, Moscow, Russia.

Lecturer, Department of CS & IT, The University of Lahore, Lahore, Pakistan. Nov 2016 - 2017

Taught courses: • Computer Vision, • Data Structures and Algorithms, • Digital Logic Design, • Business Computing, • Programming Fundamentals - I, • Introduction to Information and

Communication Technologies.

Note: All taught courses materials are available at: https://raoumer.github.io/courses.html

Given Seminars

May 2020	Deep Neural Networks for Super-Resolution, Deep Learning and more for Computer Vision Applications seminar, Universit Politecnica delle Marche (UNIVPM), Italy.
Aug 2016	Deep Learning & GPUs, Introduction to DNNs workshop, Pakistan Institute of Engineering and Applied Sciences (PIEAS), Islamabad, Pakistan.
FEB 2016	Implementation of Linear Regression and Multi-variate Regression on GPU using Cuda C/C++, GPU Computing workshop, Pakistan Institute of Engineering and Applied Sciences (PIEAS), Islamabad, Pakistan.

Research Publications Conference Publications:

Conference Publications:	
NEURIPS 2021	Rao Muhammad Umer, and Christian Micheloni. "RBSRICNN: Raw Burst Super-Resolution through Iterative Convolutional Neural Network". In proceedings of the 35th Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Workshops, December 06–14, 2021, Australia.
SPLITECH 2021	Rao Muhammad Umer, Asad Munir, and Christian Micheloni. "A Deep Residual Star Generative Adversarial Network for multi-domain Image Super-Resolution". In proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Smart and Sustainable Technologies, Sept. 08–11, 2021, Croatia.
CVPR 2021	Goutam Bhat, Martin Danelljan, Radu Timofte, and others. "NTIRE 2021 Challenge on Burst Super-Resolution: Methods and Results". In proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops, June 19–25, 2021, USA.
ICPR 2020	Rao Muhammad Umer, Gian Luca Foresti, and Christian Micheloni. "Deep Iterative Residual Convolutional Network for Single Image Super-Resolution". In proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR), Jan 10–15, 2021, Italy.
ECCV 2020	Rao Muhammad Umer, and Christian Micheloni. "Deep Cyclic Generative Adversarial Residual Convolutional Networks for Real Image Super-Resolution". In proceedings of European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Workshops, August 24–28, 2020, UK.
ECCV 2020	Pengxu Wei, Hannan Lu, Radu Timofte, Liang Lin, Wangmeng Zuo, and others. "AIM 2020 Challenge on Real Image Super-Resolution: Methods and Results". In proceedings of European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Workshops, August 24–28, 2020, UK.
ECCV 2020	Kai Zhang, Martin Danelljan, Yawei Li, Radu Timofte and others. "AIM 2020 Challenge on Efficient Super-Resolution: Methods and Results". In proceedings of European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Workshops, August 24–28, 2020, UK.
CVPR 2020	Rao Muhammad Umer, Gian Luca Foresti, and Christian Micheloni. "Deep Generative Adversarial Residual Convolutional Networks for Real-World Super-Resolution". In proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops, June 14–19, 2020, USA.
CVPR 2020	Andreas Lugmayr, Martin Danelljan, Radu Timofte, and others. "NTIRE 2020 Challenge on Real-World Image Super-Resolution: Methods and Results". In proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops, June 14–19, 2020, USA.
ICDSC 2019	Rao Muhammad Umer, Gian Luca Foresti, and Christian Micheloni. "Deep Super-Resolution Network for Single Image Super-Resolution with Realistic Degradations". In 13 th International Conference on Distributed Smart Cameras (ICDSC), Sept. 9-11, 2019, Trento, Italy.

Theses and Dissertation: **UNIUD 2021** Rao Muhammad Umer. "Deep Convolutional Neural Networks for Image Super-Resolution". Ph.D. dissertation, Department of Industrial and Information Engineering, University of Udine (UNIUD), Udine, Italy. **PIEAS 2016** Rao Muhammad Umer. "Deep Web Extractor (DWX): Content Discovery From Deep Web Using Large Scale Data Analytics Paradigm". MS Thesis, Pakistan Institute of Engineering and Applied Sciences (PIEAS), Islamabad, Pakistan. IUB 2014 Rao Muhammad Umer. "Spam Filtering System: Malicious Email Detection and Filtering System Using Bayesian Machine Learning Algorithm". Technical Report, The Islamia University of Bahawalpur (IUB), Bahawalpur, Pakistan. Reviewing Activities Journal Reviewer Transaction on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL). Conference International Conference of Pattern Recognition (ICPR). Reviewer AI Summer Schools Aug 2021 Oxford Machine Learning Summer School, (Virtual) in August 9–20, 2021, at University of Oxford, UK. Jun 2019 AI-DLDA 2019 International Summer School on Artificial Intelligence, in June 3–7, 2019, at University of Udine, Italy. Honors and Awards Nov 2018 - 2021 PhD Fellowship, sponsored by Italian Govt. for PhD studies. Oct 2016 Best MS Thesis Award, from the Department of Computer and Information Sciences, PIEAS, Islamabad, Pakistan. Nov 2014 - 2016 MS Fellowship, sponsored by the PIEAS IT-Endowment Fund for MS studies. SEP 2010 - 2014 Fully Funded National ICT Scholarship, sponsored by the National ICT $R \, \& \, D \, Fund \, for \, BSc. \, studies.$ Position Scholarship, by University College of Engineering and Technology, The Jun 2011 - 2014 Islamia University of Bahawalpur for excellent academic performance throughout undergraduate degree. SEP 2010 - 2014 Merit Scholarship, by Punjab Educational Endowment Fund(PEEF) for excellent academic performance in higher secondary school examination.

Skills

SEP 2008 - 2010

Mar 2006 - 2008

Languages • Native: Urdu, Punjabi • English: Fluent Hobbies • Cricket, Running • Reading World History Programming Python, C/C++, Java, MATLAB. Scientific Software Pytorch, Cuda C/C++, Numpy, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, Flask, Git, Latex. Computer Skills Experienced in managing Linux and Windows systems.

Merit Scholarship, by Multan Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education

Merit Scholarship, by Multan Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education

for excellent academic performance in secondary school examination.

for excellent academic performance in District level school examination.